<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>To the right honourable the House of Peeres now assembled in Parliament. The humble petition of the knights, gentlemen, freeholders, and other inhabitants of the county of Surrey, with above 2000 hands.</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 4KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 2 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B06142</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">53981755</idno>
  <idno type="VID">180394</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2240862497</idno>
  
            <idno type="STC">Wing T1636</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R185232</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">53981755</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B06142)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 180394)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English Books, 1641-1700 ; 2827:23)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>To the right honourable the House of Peeres now assembled in Parliament. The humble petition of the knights, gentlemen, freeholders, and other inhabitants of the county of Surrey, with above 2000 hands.</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.)   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed by F.L. for T. Bates,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1641 [i.e. 1642]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Caption title.</note>
                  <note>Initial letter.</note>
                  <note>Dated according to Lady-Day dating.</note>
                  <note>"Presented with the consent and approbation of the honourable House of Commons. Feb. 5. 1641 [i.e. 1642]"--colophon.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="geographic_name">Great Britain --  History --  Civil War, 1642-1649 --  Sources.</term>
               <term type="geographic_name">Surrey (England) --  History --  17th century --  Sources.</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Broadsides --  England --  17th century.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014-04 </date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-06 </date>
            <label>John Pas </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-06 </date>
            <label>John Pas</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="petition">
            <pb facs="tcp:180394:1"/>
            <head>TO THE RIGHT HONORABLE THE HOVSE OE PEERES Now assembled in Parliament.</head>
            <head type="sub">The Humble Petition of the Knights, Gentlemen, Freeholders and others Inhabitants of the County of <hi>Surrey,</hi> with above 2000. hands.</head>
            <opener>Sheweth,</opener>
            <p>
               <seg rend="decorInit">T</seg>Hat your Lordships happy concurrence with the House of Commons, in the pasing many bills for the generall good of this Kingdome, especially in your late joyning with them in your votes, for the setling the <hi>Militia</hi> and Forts in such hands as the Common-wealth may confide in, and the Kingdome in such a posture as may be for it's defence and safeguard, hath beene long the earnest desire, and is the present joy of your petitioners, yet we cannot but very much condole the miserable condition of the poore distressed Protestants in <hi>Ireland,</hi> who through the great delay which hath beene found amongst your Lordships, notwithstanding the pressing endeavours of the House of Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mons, together with many of your Lordships in sending timely reliefe unto them, have beene exposed to the inhumane cruelties of their mercylesse and Barbarous enemies, to the great dishonour of this Nation, the losse well neere of that part of his Majesties dominions, and apparent danger of the rest.</p>
            <p>With the like griefe we apprehend the fearefull distractions of this Nation, the composer of which is altogether hopelesse, so long as the Sacred Throne of his Gracious Maiesty is surrounded with evill Councellors of state producing (besides other dange<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rous effects, the high and unheard of breaches of the Priviledges of Parliament, your Lordships and our common birth-rights, and so long as the votes of Popish Lords and Bishops are continued in your House, to the animating of the Papists in th<gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>se Kingdomes in their pernitious practices, and the retarding of our generally desired reformation, and so long as our Churches doe abound with superstitious Clergy-men, many of whom lying under the censure of Parliament, for their owne securety breed and toment dev<gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>sions and factions, thereby to threat and overthrow the proceedings of this Parliament.</p>
            <p>Wherefore your Petitioners doe humbly pray and beseech this Honorable House, that you would goe on in a constant Vnion wit<gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> the House of Commons, in providing for the Kingdomes safety, by putting the <hi>Melitia</hi> and Forts into such hands as shall be recommended by both Houses, that you would expedite a continuall supply according to the emergent necessities of almost ruined <hi>Ireland,</hi> that all evill councellors (the immediate causes of our present distractions may bee found out and brought to con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>digne punishment.</p>
            <p>That the Votes of Popish Lords and the Bishops the maine obstructors of passing many good Bills, may be speedily remo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ved; that the Church may be purged of all corrupt and scandalous Ministers, That the Popish Recusants may be more then superfi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cially disarmed, and some way found out by your wisedomes, for the detecting of Church Papists, as most dangerous to this State, that so the peace of the Kingdome may be established, the priviledges of Parliament vindicated and secured to posterity, the puri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty of Religion setled and preserved.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>And the Petitioners shall ever in duty be obliged to defend and maintaine with their lives and estates, his Maiesties Roy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>all Person Crowne and Dignitie and your Lordships, so farre as you shall be united with the Honorable House of Commons in all their iust and pious proceedings.</hi>
            </p>
            <closer>And your Petitioners shall ever pray, &amp;c.</closer>
            <closer>
               <dateline>
                  <hi>Presented with the consent and approbation of the Honourable House of Commons.</hi>
                  <date>Feb. 5. 1641.</date>
               </dateline>
            </closer>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>
               <hi>London,</hi> printed by <hi>F. L.</hi> for <hi>T. Bates.</hi> 1641.</p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>